<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Pinjun Zheng&#39;s Page</title>
  <icon>https://www.gravatar.com/avatar/00b94cd35449c4c92db83df66fb0ac98</icon>
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://zpinjun.github.io/main/"/>
  <updated>2020-07-25T09:03:48.977Z</updated>
  <id>https://zpinjun.github.io/main/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Pinjun Zheng</name>
    <email>zhengpinjun@126.com</email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>China Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling, the second prize</title>
    <link href="https://zpinjun.github.io/main/2020/07/25/20190419-CUMCM-Contest/"/>
    <id>https://zpinjun.github.io/main/2020/07/25/20190419-CUMCM-Contest/</id>
    <published>2020-07-25T08:53:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-25T09:03:48.977Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>China Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling (CUMCM) is the largest mathematical modeling contest in the world. It is sponsored by China Society for Industrial and applied Mathematics. Here is the <a href="http://www.mcm.edu.cn/index_cn.html" target="_blank"><font color="#FF0000"> homepage</font></a> of CUMCM.</p><p>My friends Tanci Chen, Haopeng Liu and I participated in the 2018 CUMCM, and we won the second prize. This contest is in Chinese, and below are the problem we chose and final solution paper we submitted.</p><div class="row">    <embed src="./CUMCM-2018-Problem-A-Chinese.pdf" width="100%" height="550" type="application/pdf"></div><div class="row">    <embed src="./A201808007169_陈叹辞_郑品军_刘浩鹏.pdf" width="100%" height="550" type="application/pdf"></div>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;China Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling (CUMCM) is the largest mathematical modeling contest in the world. It is sponsored b
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
      <category term="Contest" scheme="https://zpinjun.github.io/main/tags/Contest/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weighted Phase Retrieval of Fourier Measurement with Outliers&amp;#58 Measurement Structure and Reconstruction Algorithm</title>
    <link href="https://zpinjun.github.io/main/2020/07/25/20200725-WeightedPhaseRetrieval/"/>
    <id>https://zpinjun.github.io/main/2020/07/25/20200725-WeightedPhaseRetrieval/</id>
    <published>2020-07-25T07:19:59.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-25T07:26:15.510Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Abstract"><a href="#Abstract" class="headerlink" title="Abstract"></a>Abstract</h1><p>Phaseless measurement is widely used in various fields, and phase retrieval is a key step in signal reconstruction of phaseless measurement. The occurrence of outliers will cause the optimal solution of the traditional phase retrieval objective function to deviate from the original signal, thereby reducing the reconstruction accuracy. This paper proposes to modify the objective function by introducing a weight vector or matrix so that its optimal solution will still approximate the original signal when outliers appear, and proposes a specific implementation strategy for this idea under the background of Fourier phase retrieval. We proposes a two-channel measurement structure, using discrete Fourier transform frequency domain cyclic shift theorem and mask technique to obtain a weight vector or matrix. For the improved objective function, we use the majorization-minimization framework to derive an iterative algorithm to get optimal solution. Extensive simulation and hardware experiments show that the proposed method can effectively suppress the adverse effects of outliers.</p><h1 id="Main-work"><a href="#Main-work" class="headerlink" title="Main work"></a>Main work</h1><p>The main work of this research can be summarized as follows.</p><p>(1) We propose a measurement structure of two-channel parallel measurement for phaseless Fourier measurement. By using the mask technique and the discrete Fourier transformation frequency domain cyclic shift theorem, the reliability of each measurement data can be roughly measured. At locations where outliers or strong noises appear, the reliability is correspondingly low. In normal areas, reliability is higher. This method of obtaining the reliability of the measurement data through the two-channel measurement structure can provide guidance for the phase recovery process.</p><p>(2) By introducing a weight vector or matrix, we modify the objective function of phase recovery so that its solution can still be close to the original signal under phaseless Fourier measurement with additive noise and outliers. Besides, drawing on the principle of the PRIME algorithm, we use the majorization-minimization framework to design a new phase recovery algorithm for the improved objective function. For the mapping parameter in the proposed measurement structure, we have done a lot of Monte Carlo experiments to provide empirical guidance for choosing the best value of this parameter.</p><p>(3) We perform a large number of simulation experiments to verify the performance of the proposed algorithm. Compared with other phase recovery algorithms, our algorithm is highly robust to outliers in phaseless Fourier measurement because of the introduction of reliability weights. Besides, we verified the actual operability of the proposed measurement structure and phase recovery algorithm through hardware experiments. The experimental results show that our proposed measurement structure and phase recovery algorithm can effectively eliminate the effects of outliers and reconstruct the original signal with high accuracy.</p><h1 id="Simulation-results"><a href="#Simulation-results" class="headerlink" title="Simulation results"></a>Simulation results</h1><div style="width:100%;margin:auto"><img src="/2020/07/25/20200725-WeightedPhaseRetrieval/2020-07-22_203049.png" class title="image"></div><div style="width:100%;margin:auto"><img src="/2020/07/25/20200725-WeightedPhaseRetrieval/2020-07-22_205041.png" class title="image"></div><h1 id="Hardware-experiment"><a href="#Hardware-experiment" class="headerlink" title="Hardware experiment"></a>Hardware experiment</h1><div style="width:100%;margin:auto"><img src="/2020/07/25/20200725-WeightedPhaseRetrieval/2020-07-22_205142.png" class title="image"></div>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;Abstract&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Abstract&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Abstract&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Phaseless measurement is widely used in variou
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
      <category term="Research" scheme="https://zpinjun.github.io/main/tags/Research/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Novel Phase Retrieval Algorithm for Parameterized Signal</title>
    <link href="https://zpinjun.github.io/main/2020/06/09/20200609-parameterizedPR/"/>
    <id>https://zpinjun.github.io/main/2020/06/09/20200609-parameterizedPR/</id>
    <published>2020-06-09T14:33:21.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-09T15:22:48.041Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Introduction"><a href="#Introduction" class="headerlink" title="Introduction"></a>Introduction</h1><p>Using the notation $[n]_k:=\{k,k+1,\dots,k+n-1\}$，specially，$[n]:=[n]_0$. And the notation $\widehat{\mathbf{X}_N}$ represents $N$ point DFT of $\mathbf{x}$.</p><p>In phase Fourier retrieval problem, we consider taht original signal $\mathbf{s}\in\mathbb{C}^M$，and measurement $\mathbf{y}\in\mathbb{R}^N$. The following relationship is satisfied between the two signal:<br>    \begin{equation}<br>        \mathbf{y}[n] = | \widehat{\mathbf{S}_N}[n] |^2, \forall n\in[N].<br>    \end{equation}<br>The goal of the phase retrieval problem is to reconstruct $\mathbf{s}$ from $\mathbf{y}$.</p><p>In this study we assume that the original signal conforms to the form $s(t)=\sum\limits_{k=1}^Kc_kh(t-t_k)$. In discrete form, $\mathbf{s}[m]=\sum\limits_{k=1}^Kc_k\mathbf{h}[m-m_k], \forall m\in [M]$. Because this kind of signal is completely determined by a limited number of parameters, we call it a parameterized signal. Under this assumption, recovering the original signal is equivalent to recovering $2K$ parameters $\{c_1,c_2,\dots,c_K\}$ and $\{m_1,m_2,\dots,m_K\}$. </p><h1 id="Solution"><a href="#Solution" class="headerlink" title="Solution"></a>Solution</h1><p>At present, we have completed a super-linear convergence iterative algorithm to solve the amplitude parameters.  However, for delay parameters, most of the traditional methods are based on search algorithms.  The disadvantage of this kind of method is that it will generate a huge amount of calculation for large-scale signals, and we next want to focus on avoiding this problem.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;Introduction&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Introduction&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Introduction&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using the notation $[n]_k:=\{k
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
      <category term="Research" scheme="https://zpinjun.github.io/main/tags/Research/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Measurement Fault Elimination Method in 1D Fourier Phase Retrieval</title>
    <link href="https://zpinjun.github.io/main/2020/06/09/I2MTC-paper/"/>
    <id>https://zpinjun.github.io/main/2020/06/09/I2MTC-paper/</id>
    <published>2020-06-09T02:32:06.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-22T13:09:31.378Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This research was published in 2020 IEEE International Instrumentation &amp; Measurement Technology Conference (I2MTC), May 2020.</p><h1 id="Abstract"><a href="#Abstract" class="headerlink" title="Abstract"></a>Abstract</h1><p>This paper proposes a measurement fault elimination method applied to Fourier phase retrieval. In the phase retrieval problem, if the diffraction pattern is partially measured incorrectly, the accuracy of reconstruction results will be reduced. This paper considers one-dimensional Fourier phase retrieval and proposes a method that can search the faulty measurements out by comparing Fourier magnitude of different oversampling multiples, thus is possible to filter out pixels that are not working properly in the detector to improve the reconstruction algorithm. Numerical experiments show that the method proposed in this paper can effectively eliminate the influence of faulty measurement and obtain accurate reconstruction.</p><h1 id="Online-paper"><a href="#Online-paper" class="headerlink" title="Online paper"></a>Online paper</h1><p><a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9129305" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9129305</a></p><h1 id="Presentation"><a href="#Presentation" class="headerlink" title="Presentation"></a>Presentation</h1><p>This is my presentation at I2MTC 2020:<br>(Because github page does not allow loading in iframe, please see this video on: <a href="https://youtu.be/E93YnTJK_pw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://youtu.be/E93YnTJK_pw</a>)</p><div style="width:100%;margin:auto"><img src="/2020/06/09/I2MTC-paper/2020-06-15_122502.png" class title="image"></div>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;This research was published in 2020 IEEE International Instrumentation &amp;amp; Measurement Technology Conference (I2MTC), May 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
      <category term="Research" scheme="https://zpinjun.github.io/main/tags/Research/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>ZYNQ-based Airborne AC Multi-channel Parallel Data Acquisition and Processing Board</title>
    <link href="https://zpinjun.github.io/main/2019/10/08/20200608-%E6%9C%AC%E7%A7%91%E6%AF%95%E8%AE%BE/"/>
    <id>https://zpinjun.github.io/main/2019/10/08/20200608-%E6%9C%AC%E7%A7%91%E6%AF%95%E8%AE%BE/</id>
    <published>2019-10-08T11:49:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-09T15:35:02.646Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Introduction"><a href="#Introduction" class="headerlink" title="Introduction"></a>Introduction</h1><p>Among the various electrical parameters of airborne AC, the voltage effective value (rms value) of steady-state AC voltage is an extremely important parameter. There are strict international standards for measuring the effective value of airborne AC. Our project is carried out with reference to the ISO 12384 standard. The main features of airborne AC voltage acquisition task are: </p><ul><li>Multiple acquisition channels</li><li>High sampling frequency requirements</li><li>strict synchronization requirements </li><li>Equipment miniaturization requirements</li></ul><p>Considering that the complete test system also needs to measure other parameters, which will result in a large computing power load, we want to develop a lower computer circuit to undertake the multi-channel airborne AC rms measurement task to reduce the burden on the upper computer.</p><h1 id="Technical-Requirements"><a href="#Technical-Requirements" class="headerlink" title="Technical Requirements"></a>Technical Requirements</h1><ul><li>Equipment area is not less than 200 mm × 180 mm, height is not more than 100 mm.</li><li>The sampling rate of the single voltage acquisition channel is not less than 100 ksps, and the sampling time is not more than 1s. The data bit width is not less than 14 bits.</li><li>The voltage rms error does not exceed 0.5%.</li><li>The number of acquisition channels is not less than 64, and the data of all the channels need to be acquired synchronously.</li><li>The processed data is output using the standard RS 422 interface.</li></ul><h1 id="Overall-Design"><a href="#Overall-Design" class="headerlink" title="Overall Design"></a>Overall Design</h1><h3 id="Hardware-Design"><a href="#Hardware-Design" class="headerlink" title="Hardware Design"></a>Hardware Design</h3><div style="width:70%;margin:auto"><img src="/2019/10/08/20200608-%E6%9C%AC%E7%A7%91%E6%AF%95%E8%AE%BE/2020-06-08_201007.png" class title="image"></div><p>The circuit hardware is mainly divided into the following four modules:</p><ul><li>Multi-channel data acquisition module</li><li>ZYNQ core board main control module</li><li>Data export module</li><li>Power supply module</li></ul><h3 id="Software-Design"><a href="#Software-Design" class="headerlink" title="Software Design"></a>Software Design</h3><p>The ZYNQ chip used in this project is a all programmable SoC, which equipped with dual-core ARM Cortex-A9 processors (PS) and Kintex®-7 based programmable logic (PL). We use Verilog language to program PL part to control multiple AD chips to complete the parallel acquisition and data stream transmission task of instantaneous voltage. Use the C language to develop the PS part to complete the calculation of the effective value. The logic of the PL part is packaged into an IP core through the VIVADO software, and the ARM program controls the work of these IPs by reading and writing custom registers. The following figure shows the logical state machine of one of the IP cores:</p><img src="/2019/10/08/20200608-%E6%9C%AC%E7%A7%91%E6%AF%95%E8%AE%BE/2020-06-08_223915.png" class title="image"><p>The overall operation process of the software is shown in the following figure:<br><img src="/2019/10/08/20200608-%E6%9C%AC%E7%A7%91%E6%AF%95%E8%AE%BE/2020-06-08_201345.png" class title="image"></p><ol><li>The ARM processor sends a PS_en rising edge trigger to the data master IP.</li><li>The data master IP works, data is sampled and sent into the FIFO, which loop 1000 times.</li><li>The data master IP sends PS_acquiDataOver to the ARM processor. </li><li>The ARM processor starts the DMA transfer channel. </li><li>The DMA controller transfers the data in the FIFO to the DDR memory. </li><li>The DMA controller sends a signal to the ARM processor that the transfer is complete. </li><li>The ARM processor reads data from the DDR memory.</li><li>The ARM processor performs effective value calculation and exports the result to IP through RS422.</li></ol><h1 id="Product-amp-Test"><a href="#Product-amp-Test" class="headerlink" title="Product &amp; Test"></a>Product &amp; Test</h1><img src="/2019/10/08/20200608-%E6%9C%AC%E7%A7%91%E6%AF%95%E8%AE%BE/2020-06-08_201745.png" class title="image"><img src="/2019/10/08/20200608-%E6%9C%AC%E7%A7%91%E6%AF%95%E8%AE%BE/2020-06-08_201852.png" class title="image"><ul><li>Single channel sampling rate is 167.79 ksps.</li><li>the average time for any channel of the board to complete a data acquisition and calculation process is about 6.590 ms.</li><li>The effective value acquisition error does not exceed 0.4%.</li><li>The power consumption of the whole board is about 7.98 W.</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;Introduction&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Introduction&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Introduction&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among the various electrical p
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
      <category term="Project" scheme="https://zpinjun.github.io/main/tags/Project/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Embedded Tetris game based on FPGA and VGA protocol</title>
    <link href="https://zpinjun.github.io/main/2019/08/01/20200427-%E5%A8%81%E6%B5%B7%E6%9A%91%E6%9C%9F%E5%AD%A6%E6%A0%A1%E7%BA%AA%E5%AE%9E/"/>
    <id>https://zpinjun.github.io/main/2019/08/01/20200427-%E5%A8%81%E6%B5%B7%E6%9A%91%E6%9C%9F%E5%AD%A6%E6%A0%A1%E7%BA%AA%E5%AE%9E/</id>
    <published>2019-08-01T08:23:32.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-15T04:57:27.029Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Summer-Project-of-Measurement-and-Control"><a href="#Summer-Project-of-Measurement-and-Control" class="headerlink" title="Summer Project of Measurement and Control"></a>Summer Project of Measurement and Control</h1><p>We take part in 2019 summer project of measurement and control in Weihai, China. See details about <a href="http://tce.hit.edu.cn/news/1488" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Admission Notice</a> 、<a href="https://www.hitwh.edu.cn/2019/0715/c1307a110158/page.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">News</a> and <a href="https://a.eqxiu.com/s/CEA14EuC?eqrcode=1&amp;share_level=5&amp;from_user=202004275378cf24&amp;from_id=8f96cfe4-c&amp;share_time=1587953016799&amp;from=timeline&amp;isappinstalled=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Brochure</a>。</p><p>This year’s summer project is held in Weihai, from July 14th to July 26th.  I submitted the registration form on June 25 and received the admission notice on July 4.</p><div style="width:100%;margin:auto"><img src="/2019/08/01/20200427-%E5%A8%81%E6%B5%B7%E6%9A%91%E6%9C%9F%E5%AD%A6%E6%A0%A1%E7%BA%AA%E5%AE%9E/1.jpg" class title="image"></div><h1 id="Project"><a href="#Project" class="headerlink" title="Project"></a>Project</h1><p>We have to form a team of 3 to 4 people to develop a complete work in a week.  Fortunately, my good friends Y. and P. were at the time, so we successfully formed an efficient team.</p><p>The title of the project we selected is “Embedded Tetris game based on FPGA and VGA protocol”. We use a Xilinx development board provided by the organizer, using VIVADO software and Verilog language for development. Unlike other software programming, we use FPGA to develop game logic, use five buttons on the development board as input to control the movement and rotation of Tetris, and the output is connected to the display using a VGA bus.  We use the VGA protocol to control the output logic to make the display screen display what we want to display. Our project references <a href="https://github.com/rfotino/verilog-tetris" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this</a> open source project. On the basis of the existing we have added several new functions:</p><ul><li>Display the next Tetris in the upper left corner of the interface.</li><li>Display the current score in the upper right corner of the interface (the original project is to display the score on the development board with a digital tube).</li><li>The opening image is displayed at the beginning of the game, and the ending image is displayed at the end of the game.</li></ul><p>Our project can be found on my <a href="https://github.com/ZPinjun/Tetris-base-on-FPGA-VGA" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Github</a> and <a href="https://download.csdn.net/download/qq_39065549/12168594" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CSDN</a>.</p><p>The difficulty of the work we do is the display of images.  Because VGA controls the three RGB color channels in the form of dot matrix scanning, it is relatively easy to implement regular geometric figures such as squares.  To display the image in hardware language, we must first store the digital image information in RAM, and then send it to the VGA bus according to the mapping relationship during display.  In order to achieve this, we first use the drawing tool to design the image we want to display, and then use Matlab to read the information of the digital image, convert the information of each pixel into a binary number, and then follow a certain order (three channels separate,  The sequence is R&gt;G&gt;B. Each channel is scanned line by line, from top to bottom.). Write it to the .txt file according to the format of the .coe file, and finally change the suffix to .coe to obtain the storage information recognized by VIVADO. Then integrate the module into the project. Before the game starts, first output the image information in the .coe file to the VGA. Note that it must be output strictly in the order set before.</p><p>Fortunately, our work was finally rated as an excellent work. The following is a display taken at the time:<br>(Because github page does not allow loading in iframe, please see this video on: <a href="https://youtu.be/LLhhkAAC9Gc" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://youtu.be/LLhhkAAC9Gc</a>)</p><div style="width:100%;margin:auto"><img src="/2019/08/01/20200427-%E5%A8%81%E6%B5%B7%E6%9A%91%E6%9C%9F%E5%AD%A6%E6%A0%A1%E7%BA%AA%E5%AE%9E/2.jpg" class title="image"></div>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;Summer-Project-of-Measurement-and-Control&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Summer-Project-of-Measurement-and-Control&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Summer Pro
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
      <category term="Project" scheme="https://zpinjun.github.io/main/tags/Project/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Mathematical Contest in Modeling, Meritorious Winner</title>
    <link href="https://zpinjun.github.io/main/2019/04/25/20190419-MCM-Contest/"/>
    <id>https://zpinjun.github.io/main/2019/04/25/20190419-MCM-Contest/</id>
    <published>2019-04-25T07:30:21.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-25T09:09:55.035Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Mathematical Contest in Modeling (MCM) is an international contest sponsored by COMAP (the Consortium for Mathematics and Its Application). It challenges teams of students to clarify, analyze, and propose solutions to open-ended problems. The contest attracts diverse students and faculty advisors from over 900 institutions around the world. Here is the <a href="https://www.comap.com/undergraduate/contests/index.html" target="_blank"><font color="#FF0000"> homepage</font></a> of MCM.</p><p>My friends Tanci Chen, Yiming Li and I participated in the 2019 MCM, and we won the Meritorious Winner. The time spent working hard with trusted partners is unforgettable. We have recorded and summarized this wonderful experience on this<a href="https://upupming.site/2019/01/29/2019-mcm-summary/#前期准备" target="_blank"><font color="#FF0000"> page</font></a>. </p><div style="width:60%;margin:auto"><img src="/2019/04/25/20190419-MCM-Contest/2020-07-25_154907.png" class title="image"></div><p>Here is the problem we chose:  </p><div class="row">    <embed src="./2019_MCM_Problem_A.pdf" width="100%" height="550" type="application/pdf"></div><p>Here is our solution paper at the time: </p><div class="row">    <embed src="./MCM_solution_paper.pdf" width="100%" height="550" type="application/pdf"></div>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;The Mathematical Contest in Modeling (MCM) is an international contest sponsored by COMAP (the Consortium for Mathematics and Its Applica
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
      <category term="Contest" scheme="https://zpinjun.github.io/main/tags/Contest/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Handheld Medical Terminal Development Based on Qt</title>
    <link href="https://zpinjun.github.io/main/2018/08/09/20200609-neusoft/"/>
    <id>https://zpinjun.github.io/main/2018/08/09/20200609-neusoft/</id>
    <published>2018-08-09T04:05:43.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-09T15:34:20.109Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Introduction"><a href="#Introduction" class="headerlink" title="Introduction"></a>Introduction</h1><p>2018.7.16—2018.7.26, a short-term internship at Neusoft Group Co., Ltd. We developed a integrated software based on Qt for a handheld device for doctors to manage and monitor the patients’ physiological data, e.g. blood pressure and glucose level. My main job is to program with Qt to collect and visualize data from handheld devices in real time.</p><h1 id="Product"><a href="#Product" class="headerlink" title="Product"></a>Product</h1><p>Login interface:</p><div style="width:70%;margin:auto"><img src="/2018/08/09/20200609-neusoft/1.png" class title="image"></div><p>Main interface:</p><div style="width:70%;margin:auto"><img src="/2018/08/09/20200609-neusoft/2.png" class title="image"></div><p>Patient information query interface:</p><div style="width:70%;margin:auto"><img src="/2018/08/09/20200609-neusoft/3.png" class title="image"></div><p>Patient blood pressure data query and visualization:</p><div style="width:70%;margin:auto"><img src="/2018/08/09/20200609-neusoft/4.png" class title="image"></div><div style="width:70%;margin:auto"><img src="/2018/08/09/20200609-neusoft/5.png" class title="image"></div>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;Introduction&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Introduction&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Introduction&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;2018.7.16—2018.7.26, a short-t
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
      <category term="Internship" scheme="https://zpinjun.github.io/main/tags/Internship/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
